

Contact

Phone

+923168270946

Email

durrahkhan555@gmail.com

Address

56 A1 Homes, High Court Society PIA Road, Johar Town Lahore / Pakistan

Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/durrah-khan-1a3660171/

GitHub

https://github.com/mrbaloch555

Expertise

- Back end Engineer
- Front end Engineer
- Data Scientist Engineer
- Machine Learning Engineer
- Deep Learning Engineer
- Computer Vision
- MongoDB Database System

Language

English

Urdu

Balochi

Durrah Khan

Backend Engineer / Data Scientist

I am a Nodejs Backend Engineer and a Data Scientist. Designed multiple Web applications with javascript frameworks and libraries, designed and trained Deep Models, creates prediction and recommendation systems, and also worked in Computer vision for object detection using python libraries and frameworks. Used different databases for application development both SQL and No-SQL and much more experienced with No-SQL databases (MongoDB). Designed web backend Rest Apis for web applications and mobile applications using Nodejs and Express framework. I am also experienced with python web frameworks and created Rest API with python flask restful. I always like clean coding and following design patterns for my applications. Love to work and solve complex problems.

Experience

07/2022 - Present ELITE IT LIMITED

Back end Engineer

- Gathered and validated requirements as a part of a collaboration for a progressive web application that helped develop clear, unambiguous technical requirements and establish a consistent feedback loop.
- Coordinated with 3 other teams to identify customer requirements, creating 16+ BRD and tech documents that streamlined development activities.
- Performed full-stack development of the high-profile external web app,
- Maintained newly developed and existing systems for a mission-critical
- Deployed applications on digital ocean and Amazon EC2 servers.
- Set up HTTPS configurations.
- Optimized legacy data storage and search queries for the high-volume.

\ 05/2022 - 09/2022

FREELANCER

Data Scientist

- Deployed a recommendation engine to production to conditionally recommend other menu items based on past order history, increasing average order size by 7%
- Designed a Virtual Assistant chatbot for a company with application-specific queries and answers
- Developed a movie recommendation system for a client for their web-based application and deployed them on Amazon EC2.
- Work on various data science projects and cleaned different kinds of data using python libraries.
- Worked on selenium web driver and scrap data from different websites with help for beautiful soup.

06/2021- 05/2022 STACK INTEL IO

Full Stack MERN Web Developer

- Backend Web development using (Nodejs, Express, and MongoDB).
- Frontend Development with Reactjs and Redux Saga.
- Database replication implementation with authentication is supported for the smooth running
- of servers. Replication of files from one server to another server for availability of files
- Writing efficient and fast Mongo Database queries (Filtering, Aggregation, Bulk Write
- operations, Index Searching) to reduce the load on the server.
- Design Rest APIs with JWT authentication supported and integration of APIs for web
- and mobile apps.
- Developing Role based authentication system for different users with different sets of operations.
- Integration of Firebase notification system in Node for mobile apps.
- Integration of flask APIs with Node APIs to get data from flask APIs to Node APIs.
- Developed an interactive User Interface using HTML, CSS, React JS, and Ant Design.
- Implemented Redux Saga as middleware for Node.js APIs call efficient workflow, and Cron expression for pooling.

O 1/2019 - 03/2020 NET RIDERS

Full Stack MERN Web Developer

- Designed and developed User Interface using HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript Created sites using various Content Management Systems, and theming semantically with HTML, CSS and adding interactivity with JavaScript and libraries like jQuery.
- Implemented best practices in JavaScript codebase, develop new functionality and create new layouts, teach advanced JavaScript techniques to the team.
- Detect the attack and its source by analyzing network traffic data.
- Analyzed the weblog data and extract the analytics from the data, we have set up a Hadoop cluster with 10 hosts (9 DataNodes + 1 Master Node) using Cloudera Manager to process 7TB of log data.
- Traveled Package Recommendation System Environment: Web-based Data Mining Project, Java, JavaScript, MySQL Implemented a travel package recommendation service in Java using the Collaborative Filtering technique.

O 05/2020 - 12/2020 TECH LAB Java Script Developer

- Designed Front end application using front end frameworks (Ant Design, Bootstrap)
- Designed Backend application using PHP and MySQL.
- Written efficient SQL queries.
- Make sure continuous communication of backend and front end.

Education

O NOVEMBER 2021 PRESENT MS DATA SCIENCE UNIVERSITY OF THE PUNAB LAHORE COURSES

- Data Science Tools and Techniques
- Statistics and Mathematics for Data Science
- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- Digital Image Processing, Computer Vision,
- Natural Language Processing,
- Bio Informatics.

APRIL 2017 - APRIL 2021

BS INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY INSTITUTE OF SOUTHERN PUNJAB MULTAN COURSES

- Programming Fundamentals
- Object Oriented Programming
- Data Structure,
- Database Management System I
- Database Management System II
- Software Engineering
- Web Development
- Digital Image Processing.

Programming Languages

- Java Script (Nodejs, Express, ReactJs, Redux, Saga, SocketIO, CanvsJs, Recharts)
- Python (Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Tensorflow, Pytorch)
- C#

Licenses & certifications

1 JavaScript (Intermediate) Certificate

2 JavaScript (Basic) Certificate

3 Python (Basic) Certificate

https://bit.ly/3Mjc647

https://bit.ly/3Mg0X3Y

https://bit.ly/3VgsXbZ

Reference

Reference will be provided on demand